Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty; Records apap401
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Legislative Activities, 1992-2023
  - 2011 Legislation
    - Prefiled of Interest Up Through 367, 2010 December
    - Kentucky Voices for Health Priorities Document, 2010 December
    - Journal of the House of Reprsentatives of the General Assemble of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Volume 3, 1990
    - Kentucky House Districts, 2002
    - Kentucky Senate District, 2002
    - Progressive State Network, State immigration Project: Policy Opinions Guide, 2009
    - Texas Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, Seeking Justice in Texas Newsletter, 2009
    - United States District Court for the District of Arizona, U.S.A. v. State of Arizona, Declaration of James B. Steinberg, 2010
    - United States District Court for the District of Arizona, U.S.A. v. State of Arizona, Declaration of Tony Estrada, 2010
    - Immigration Legislation Outreach Sheet, 2010
    - Senate Bill 6, Scanned Copy, 2010
    - Memorandum of Agreement Between U.S. Department of Homeland Security Immigration and Customs Enforcement and Kentucky State Police, 2010
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky, Abolish the Death Penalty in Kentucky Pamphlet, 2010
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky, Abolish the Death Penalty in Kentucky Dream Act Talking Points, 2010
    - Catholics @ the Capitol DRAFT: Bulletin announcement (shorter) for Fayette Deanery parishes, 2010
    - Catholics @ the Capitol: Faithful Citizenship Bulletin, 2010
    - Catholics @ the Capitol DRAFT: First Bulletin Announcement (longer) for Fayette Deanery parishes, 2010
    - Lexington Legislators, 2010
    - Catholic Diocese of Lexington Map, 2010
    - PSA for Catholics @ the Capitol, 2010
    - Tabling- Catholics @ the Capitol Fayetter Legislators, 2010
    - "Calling all Catholic Faithful Citizens" Bishop's Invite for Western Kentucky Gatherings, 2010
    - Bulletin Announcement: Hopkinsville Region, Calling all Faithful Citizens, 2010
    - Letter to Pastors Regarding Catholics @ the Capitol: Western Kentucky Gatherings, 2010
    - List of Parishes to invite to Catholics @ the Capitol: Hopkinsville Region, 2010
    - House Bill 16 As Filed, 2010 General Assembly
    - Mentally Ill Bill Explanation, 2010
    - Draft Talking Points for House Bill 16- 2010 Kentucky General Assembly
    - Mentally Ill Bill Explanation, 2010
    - KY Forward Contact List, 2010
    - Comments on Senate Bill 6 1, 2011
    - Catholics @ the Capitol General Assembly, 2011
    - Catholics @ the Capitol General Assembly Presentation, 2011
    - American Bar Association Recommendation, Adopted by the House of Delegates, 122A, 2006 August 7-2006 August 8
    - ABA Resolution- Feature article "Recommendation and Report on the Death Penalty and Persons with Mental Disabilities", 2006 September-2006 October
  - 2012 Legislation
    - ROVRC Organization Contact List, 2006 February 3
    - Courier-Journal.com Article "Prosecutor: Ease Rigid Rules Denying Vote to Reformed Felons", 2006 November 17
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky House of Reprsentatives, House Bill 70 Vote History, 2008 April 1
    - Courier-Journal.com Editorials "Beshear Gets It", 2008 July 31
    - American Probation and Parole Association Letter and Resolution, 2008 November 14
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky "Testimony Offered in Support of BR 1" Release, 2009 January 22
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky House of Reprsentatives, House Bill 70 Vote History, 2009 February 12
    - Letter from the Department of Public Advocacy to the Judiciary Committee Reagrding the Death Penalty, 2009 February 25
    - Letter from Attorney General Jack Conway to Norman Lawson of the Judiciary Committee Regarding Cost of the Death Penalty, 2009 March 5
    - Letter from R. David Stengel Commonwealth's Attorney to Legislative Research Commission, 2009 April 14
    - Email Regarding ROVRC Study on Disenfranchisement and Kentucky, 2009 July 10
    - SMI- Death Penalty Conference Call Agenda, 2009 August 5
    - Request for a Thematic Hearing on the Discriminatory Effects of Felony Disenfranchisement Laws, Policies and Practices in the Americas Cover Page, 2009 September 8
    - Sentencing Project Report International Request Graphic, Request 107, 2009 September 8
    - Sentencing Project Report International Request Graphic, Request 108, 2009 September 8
    - Sentencing Project Report International Graphic Request 109, 2009 September 8
    - Sentencing Project Report International Graphic Request 110, 2009 September 8
    - Request for a Thematic Hearing on the Discriminatory Effects of Felony Disenfranchisement Laws, Policies and Practices in the Americas Full Report, 2009 September 8
    - Fax of Names and Addresses of Those Testifying on House Bill 70 at Interim Committee Meeting, 2009 September 30
    - New York Times Article "Group Gives Up Death Penalty Work", 2010 January 5
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky "Testimony Offered in Support of HB 70" Release, 2010 February 2
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky House of Reprsentatives, House Bill 70 Vote History, 2010 February 10
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky House of Reprsentatives, House Bill 70 Vote History, 2010 February 10
    - Fax of Names and Addresses of Those Testifying on House Bill 70, 2010 February 15
    - Jordan Steiker Testimony Regarding American Law Institute's Withdrawal of Capital Punishment, Full Version, 2010 March 1
    - Jordan Steiker Testimony Regarding American Law Institute's Withdrawal of Capital Punishment, Short Version, 2010 March 1
    - Testimony before the Pennsylvania Senate Government Management and Cost Study Commission, 2010 June 7
    - Memo Regarding Potetnial Litigation to Challenge Kentuckyu's Lifetime Felon Disenfranchisement Law Under the Eighth Amendment, 2010 August 9
    - Kentucky General Assembly, Judiciary Committee Meeting Agenda, 2010 August 11
    - Memo Regarding Thoughts on the Lawsuit, 2010 October 6
    - Letter from Pat Delahanty to Rom Tabak, 2010 October 7
    - Responses from Mental Illness Experts, 2010 November 15
    - House Bill 70 Voting Alert 1, 2011 February 7
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky House of Reprsentatives, House Bill 70 Vote History, 2011 February 10
    - Letter from Florida Parole Commission to Govenor Scott, General Bondi, CFO Atwater, and Commissioner Putnam, 2011 June 30
    - A Bill to Abolish the Death Penalty, Final Draft, 2011 October 18
    - A Bill to Abolish the Death Penalty, Draft with Team Edits, 2011 October 31
    - A Bill to Abolish the Death Penalty, Draft 2 with Edits, 2011 November 4
    - American Bar Assocation "Evaluating Fairness and Accuracy in State Death Penalty Systems: The Kentucky Death Penalty Assessment Report", 2011 November 28
    - Members of the Kentucky Death Penalty Assessment Team, 2011 November 28
    - American Bar Association Poll Findings, 2011 December 7
    - House Bill 145, An ACT relating to Mental Illness, 2011 December 18
    - Letter Template for Seeking Co-Sponsorship of House Bill 145, 2011 December 28
    - Letter from Senator Gerald Neal to Senator Jensen Asking for a Hearing, 2011 December 31
    - Corrrections Impact Statement Senate Bill 63, 2012 January 12
    - "Smart on Crime: Reconsidering the Death Penalty in a Time of Economic Crisis" Report from the Death Penalty Information Center, 2012 January 12
    - The Record Newsletter Archdiosce of Louisville, Page 4, 2012 January 12
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky "Testimony Offered in Support of HB 70" Release, 2012 January 24
    - Statement of Raoul Cunningham President of the Louisville Branch NAACP Before the House Standing Committee on Elections, Constitutional Amendments, and Intergovernmental Affairs, 2012 January 24
    - Kentucky.com Herald Leader Editorial "Return Voting Rights to Ex-Felons", 2012 January 29
    - Courier-Journal.com Editorial "Ex-felons' voting rights", 2012 January 31
    - Senate Bill 63 Fact Sheet, 2012 February 5
    - Testimony Submitted to the Kentucky Senate, Standing Committee on Judiciary, Hearings on the Cost of the Death Penalty, 2012 March 1
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky House Bill 145, Preclude the Use of the Death Penalty for Individuals with Severe Mental Illness, 2012 February 5
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky House of Reprsentatives, House Bill 70 Vote History, 2012 February 16
    - The Daily News Article "Guilty but Mentally Ill", 2012 February 17
    - Typical Death Penalty Costs, 2012 February 20
    - Constanct Contact Email Alert Regarding the House Bill 145, 2012 February 21
    - Concurrent Resolution Task Force to Implement American Bar Association's Recommendations from the Kentucky Death Penalty Assessment Report, 2012 February 28
    - Richard "Dick" Dieter Biography, 2012 February 28
    - House Bill 70 Voting Alert 2, 2012 February 29
    - Richard Dieter Testimony Submitted to the Kentucky State Standing Committee on Judiciary, Hearings on the Costs of the Death Penalty, 2012 March 1
    - Michael Mannheimer Talking Points, Kentucky Judiciary Committee, 2012 March 1
    - The Record Newsletter Archdiosce of Louisville, Page 1, 2012 March 8
    - The Record Newsletter Archdiosce of Louisville, Page 6, 2012 March 8
    - Responses to Hearing on Senate Bill 63, 2012 March 12
    - House Committee Report 173 and Other Alert Materials, 2012 March 21
    - Press Release from the League of Women Voters of Kentucky Regarding their Report "Felony Disenfranchisement in the Commonwealth of Kentucky", 2013 February 11
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky House of Reprsentatives, House Bill 70 Vote History, 2013 February 20
    - Courier-Journal.com Article "Bluegrass Poll: Kentucky Supports Restoring Felon Voting Rights", 2013 February 24
    - Courier-Journal.com Editorial "Let Voters Decide Voting Rights for Former Felons", 2013 March 3
    - Kentucky.com Article "Merlen Davis: Let Us Decide on Restoration of Felons Right to Vote", 2013 March 13
    - Kentucky Legislature HB70 07RS WWW Version, 2013 October 5
    - Kentucky Legislature HB70 08RS WWW Version, 2013 October 5
    - "Public Attitudes Towards Felon Disenfranchisement in the United States" Summary, 2013 October 15
    - Meeting with Govenor Beshear Letter from Terry Naydan, 2013 October 26
    - "Reasons to Support Restoring Voting Rights to People with Criminial Convictions in Kentucky", 2013 November 14
    - Courier-Journal Op-Ed Written by Jesse Crenshaw and Pat Delahanty, 2013 December 18
    - Catholic Conference of Kentucky "Testimony for HB 70", 2014 January 14
    - Testimony for House Bill 70 by the Catholic Conference of Kentucky, 2014 January 14
    - Division of Probation and Parole Application for Restoration of Civil Rights, 2014 January 24
    - Letter to Catholic Conference of Kentucky from the NAACP Lousiville Branch, 2014 January 29
    - Ferlony Sex Offenses in Kentucky, 2014 February 16
    - Email Regarding House Bill 70 Committee, 2014 February 19
    - Unoffical Copy of "An ACT proposing an amendment to Section 145 of the Constitution of Kentucky relating to persons entitled to vote"- 5 Year Wait, 2014 February 28
    - Kentucky Constitution, Section 145 "Persons Entitled to Vote", 2014 March 1
    - Unoffical Copy of "An ACT proposing an amendment to Section 145 of the Constitution of Kentucky relating to persons entitled to vote"- 3 Year Wait, 2014 March 1
    - Courier-Journal Article "Tom Burch Retoring Felon Voting Rights", 2014 May 8
    - "Felony Disenfranchisement in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, A Report of the League of Women Voters of Kentucky", 2006 October
    - League of Women Voters of Kentucky Flyer, Black and White, 2007 November
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 April
    - Federal Probation, Journal of Correctional Philiosophy and Practice Vol. 73 No. 1, 2009 June
    - "Voting Rights in Kentucky, Felons Who Have Completed All Terms of Their Sentences Should Have the Right to Vote" Report, 2009 September
    - The Sentencing Project, "Expanding the Vote, State Felony Disenfranchisement Refor, 1997-2010", 2010 October
    - Description of News Story in the Miami Herald About Florida Parole Commission, 2011 August
    - Kentucky Assessment Report on the Death Penalty Pamphlet, Color Version, 2011 December
    - The Sentencing Project: Research and Advocacy For Reform "Felony Disenfranchisement Laws in the United States", 2011 December
    - Felony Disenfranchisement in the Commonwealth of Kentucky: A Report of the League of Women Voters of Kentucky, 2013 January
    - Recommendations by the Govenor's Reentry Task Force Steering Committee to the Kentucky General Assembly, 2013 October
    - Mentally Ill Bill Explanation, 2010
    - Voting Rights Coalition "Support the Restoration of Voting Rights Act: HB 70" Flyer, 2010
    - Voting Rights Senate Tally Sheet, 2010
    - Voting Rights Senate Tally Sheet, 2010
    - ACLU "Breaking Barriers to the Ballot Box Felon Enfranchisement Toolkit", 2013
    - Colombia Human Rights Law Review "Voting and Subsequent Crime and Arrest: Evidence from a Community Sample", 2004-2005
    - Kentuckians Support Automatic Restoration of Voting Rights for Felons Who Have Served Their Sentences Infographic, 2006 August-2006 September
  - 2015 Legislation
    - Email Regarding "Osborne - Jury Decision", 2002 August 2
    - Death Penalty Inforamtion Center Editorial "Illinois-Outlaw Deathe Penalty to Save Lives and Cash", 2010 November 8
    - Kentucky Politics Article "Lawmakers Consider Death Penalty Abolition", 2013 January 3
    - Equal Justice USA "Conservatives are Concerned about the Death Penalty" Fact Sheet, 2013 January 15
    - KCADP Lobby Meeting Report Form Template, 2013 January 15
    - Vote Count for House Judiciary Committee, 2013 January 15
    - Email Regarding Position of Archbishop Kurtz on the Bill Supporting Recommendations masde by the Kentucky Death Penalty Asessment Team in December of 2011, 2013 February 6
    - Article "Kentucky Should Not Administer the Death Penalty", 2013 February 22
    - State Journal Op-Ed "Abolish the Death Penalty: Kentuckians Don't Want the Costly, Error-Ridden System", 2013 March 13
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Logo, 2013 July 31
    - List of Heleringer Quotes, 2013 July 31
    - Statement of Officer Tulio Torinho Sent to KCADP, 2013 September 18
    - Agenda for Meeting on Conservative Outreach, 2013 September 24
    - "Wrongfully Convicted in KY, Years Spent in Prison" Graphic, 2013 December 5
    - Article "DYCHE- Conservatives Against the Death Penalty", 2014 February 17; 2014 February 18
    - Article "A Conservative's Case for Repeal of the Death Penalty", 2014 February 23
    - Letter from Byron W. VanArsdale to the Honorable Mr. Floyd, 2014 March 7
    - The Kentucky Standaerd Article "We gain nothing from capital punishment", 2014 March 13
    - The Delaware Repeal Project "Facts about Law Enforcement Deaths by Homicide in States that Have Ended the Use of the Death Penalty since 2007, 2014 March 26
    - Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty-Fact Sheet Overview, Black and White, 2014 April 22
    - Article "Big Republican names-including potential 2015 candidates-among donors in 32nd House Dist. GOP Primary", 2014 April 25
    - Hazard-herald.com Article "Stidham Sentenced to Life in Prison", 2014 June 5
    - Letter Draft from Ray Krone at KY Witness to Innocence, 2014 July 29
    - Final Letter from Ray Krone at KY Witness to Innocence, 2014 July 29
    - Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation Letter to Senator Westerfield Regarding the Kentucky Death Penalty Hearing, 2014 July 30
    - Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation "What Do Families Need in the Aftermath of Homicide?", 2014 July 30
    - Judiciary Hearing Schedule, Specifically Meetings Regarding the Death Penalty, 2014 August 1
    - Interim Joint Committee on Judiciary Agenda, Meeting 2, 2014 August 1
    - Interim Joint Committee on Judiciary Directions, 2014 August 1
    - Judge Stephen Ryan Story, 2014 August 1
    - 532.030 Authorized Dispositions - Generally- Instructions by judge, 2014 August 1
    - Photograph of Marian and Jason Presenting, 2014 August 1
    - Paducah Sun Report Article "Many Voices Debate on Capital Punishment", 2014 August 1
    - Resources for Reporters, 2014 August 1
    - Paducah Sun Article "Death Penalty Focus of Paducah Hearing", 2014 August 1
    - KCADP "Remarks of Rev. Patrick Delahanty Prepared for Interim Joint Judiciary Committee Meeting Held August 1, 2014 in Paducah, Kentucky", 2014 August 1
    - Courier-Journal.com Article "Man Sent to Death Row is Acquited in Retrial, Original Conviction Thrown out on an Appeal; Defendant was 17 When Whitley Couple Slain", 2014 August 2
    - Daily News Article "Copass Gets Life in Prison", 2014 August 20
    - Capitol Punishment Strategy Session, 2014 September 9
    - Email Asking for Support During the Session, 2014 December 2
    - Email from Father John Moriarity Offering Support anf to Come and Rally, 2014 December 2
    - Courier-Journal.com Article "Replace the Death Penalty with Life Without Parole", 2014 December 28
    - Senate Committee Memberships (By Committee), 2015 January 5
    - "Worst of the Worst" Handout, 2015 January 13
    - 8th Amendment Project Response to Request for Information, 2016 June 24
    - Letter to State and National Campaign Partners from the 8th Amendment Project Regarding Field Questionare Response, 2017 June 12
    - KCADP Press Release "Kentucky Judiciary Committee to Hear Death Penalty Discussion", 2017 July 28
    - Kentucky Assessment Report on the Death Penalty Pamphlet, 2011 December
    - Statement of Former Commonwealth Attorney for Jefferson County, 2013 October
    - The Advocate Newsletter featuring Dr. Sandy's Juror's Study, 2014 August
    - Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation "How the Death Penalty Causes Additional Harm", 2012
    - Catholics at the Capitol General Assembly Presentation, 2013
    - Targets for Bullitt, 2013
    - Midterm Elections Debrief from the 8th Amendment Project "What do the election results mean fordeath penalty abolition efforts around the country?" Presentation, 2014
    - Midterm Elections Debrief from the 8th Amendment Project "What do the election results mean fordeath penalty abolition efforts around the country?" Slide Deck, 2014
    - No Penological Value Map, 2015 May 13
    - "The Death Penalty is Broken Beyond Repair" Map Graphic, 2014
    - "The Death Penalty is in Decline" Map Graphic, 2014
    - "Executing the Severely Mentally Ill/ Functionally Impaired Serves No Penological Purpose" Map Graphic, 2014
    - Kentucky Wrongful Convictions Chart Graphic, 2014
    - "Life without Parole: A penalty that fits Kentucky, Support SB 77 and House Bill 330", 2014
    - Kentucky.com Article "Allen Ault: Why sholuld Ky. End the Death Penalty? Ask those who carry it out", 2014
    - KCADP "Life Without Parole: A Penalty that Fits Kentucky, Support SB 77 & HB 330" Talking Points, 2014
    - Enews Alert with Gerald Bill and Berea Event, 2014
    - Twitter Handles List, 2014
    - Twitter Handles List, Conflict, 2014
    - "Winning Death Penalty Abolition at the U.S. Suprem Court" Benchmarks for Winning Abolition, 2015
    - KCADP Abolition Handout, 2015
    - LRC Staff Assignments for 2015 Standing Committee
    - KCADP "Life Without Parole: A Penalty that Fits Kentucky, Support SB 15 & HB 82" Talking Points, 2015
    - The 8th Amendment Project Polls Messaging, 2010-2014
    - National Strategy to End the Death Penalty, Five Year Plan, 2018 July 1-2023 July 1; 2021 June 29
  - 2016 Legislation
    - Meeting Summary, 2015 July 13
    - Legislator Meeting Report Form, 2015
  - 2019 Legislation
    - Snitch Bill Illinoise Senate Bill 1830, 2018 May 21
    - Senate Judiciary Home Address, 2018 June 18
    - Letter for Legislators Post-Election from the KCADP, 2018 November 6
    - Dear Representative-Elect Letter from KCADP, 2018 November 6
    - Dear Representative Letter from KCADP, 2018 November 6
    - Dear Senator-Elect Letter from KCADP, 2018 November 6
    - Dear Senator Letter from KCADP, 2018 November 6
    - Messenger-Inquirer Article "Bill Would Limit Death Penalty Cases for Mentally Ill?", 2019 January 6
    - 82 Percent of Kentucky Voters Oppose the Use of the Death Penalty for Persons with Severe Mental Illness, Chart Graphic, 2019 January 19
    - Polling Chart, Severely Mentally Ill, 2019 January 21
    - 82 Percent of Kentucky Voters Oppose the Use of the Death Penalty for Persons with Severe Mental Illness, Chart Graphic with Caption, 2019 January 21
    - Polling Chart, Victim, 2019 January 22
    - 54 Percent of Kentucky Voters Support Replacing the Death Penalty with Life Without Parole Because of Effects on Victims' Families Chart with Caption, 2019 January 22
    - Polling Chart, Prison Sentences with Question, 2019 January 24
    - Polling Chart, Prison Sentences with Question, Low Resolution for Social Media, 2019 January 24
    - Cost Chart, Low Resolution for Social Media, 2019 January 25
    - Polling chart, SMI Chart for Distribution, 2019 January 25
    - Polling chart, SMI Chart for Distribution, Low Resolution for Social Media, 2019 January 25
    - Polling chart, SMI Chart for Distribution with Attribution, Low Rsolution for Social Media, 2019 January 25
    - Polling Chart, Victim, 2019 January 25
    - Polling Chart, Victim, Low Resolution for Social Media, 2019 January 25
    - Polling Chart, Cost Factor, 2019 February 4
    - Polling Chart, Voters Attitude, 2019 February 4
    - Polling Chart, How You Would Vote, 2019 February 4
    - Polling Chart, How You Would Vote, Low Resolution for Social Media, 2019 February 4
    - Twiter Message on Senate Bill 27, 2019 February 6
    - Twitter Message Asking What the Bill Does, 2019 February 7
    - Update for Ed Harpring, 2019 February 11
    - KCADP Murder Victim Family Member Letter, 2019 February 12
    - House 2019 Status, 2019 February 25
    - Letter from KCADP Requesting Members/Interested Parties' Email Addresses, 2019 May
    - KCADP Invitation to Discuss the Use of the Death Penalty at the Capitol, 2018 December
    - Mason-Dixon Kentucky Poll, Short Version, 2018 December
    - Mason-Dixon Kentucky Poll, Full Version, 2018 December
    - Letter Regarding Senate Bill 17, An Act Relating to Serious Mental Illness, 2019 February
    - National Association of Evangelicals - "Capital Punishment", 2015
    - "Class (And Death Penalty) Dismissed: How My Years in Education Changed My Views on the Death Penalty" Article, 2017
    - Message to Father Delahanty Regarding an Analysis of the Recent Election in the Kentucky General Assembly, 2018
    - House Judiciary Home Addresses for Advocacy Efforts, 2018
    - Interim Judiciary Members and their Addresses, 2018
    - 53 Percent of Kentucky Voters Support Replacing the Death Penalty with Life Without Parole Because of High Costs Graphic, 2019
    - Abolish the Death Penalty, House Bill 115 Graphic, 2019
    - Graphic for Website Executions Down Republican Sponsors Up, 2019
    - House Bill 115 Information One Sheet, 2019
    - Regular Session -Report of Committee, 2019
    - Senate Bill 17, An Act relating to Serious Mental Illness, 2019
    - Senate Representative Candidates Unopposed, 2017-2018
    - State Senator Candidates November 6 Winners, 2017-2018
    - State Representative Canidates Winners November 6, 2017-2018
    - State Senator Candidates Unopposed, 2017-2018
  - 2020 Legislation
    - Committee Report, Regular Session 2019 Senate Committee on Judiciary, 2019 February 7
    - Serious Mental Illness Coalition Strategy, 2019 February 12
    - House 2019 Anticipated Votes, 2019 February 25
    - Testimony by Evelyn Lundberg Stratton Before the House Criminal Justice Committee, 2019 May 2